<resources>
    <string name="aboutmetext">
        "Application and System created by Brian Cunningham and Dylan Kohl.\n\n"
        "Created for ECE 461 &amp; 462 Senior Design 2018.\n\n"
        "Not for public release.\n\n"
        "Android Graphing Library by Jonas Gehring.\n\n"
        View License at \nhttps://github.com/jjoe64/GraphView"
    </string>
    <string name="learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="ppm">ppm</string>
    <string name="blank"> </string>
    <string name="last_updated_at_July_6_1989">Last Updated at July 6, 1989</string>
    <string name="time">time</string>
    <string name="Measurement">Measurement</string>
    <string name="Action">Action</string>
    <string name="Hello_There">Hello There!</string>
    <string name="Air_Temp">Air Temp</string>
    <string name="humidity">Humidity</string>
    <string name="TVOC">TVOC</string>
    <string name="CO2_Levels">CO₂ Levels</string>
    <string name="Solution_Temp">Solution Temp</string>
    <string name="TDS">TDS</string>
    <string name="Dissolved_O2">Dissolved O₂</string>
    <string name="ORP">ORP</string>
    <string name="pH">pH</string>
    <string name="degreef"> °F</string>
    <string name="percentsign">%</string>
    <string name="centimeters"> cm</string>
    <string name="mv"> mV</string>
    <string name="full">Full</string>
    <string name="notfull">Not Full</string>
    <string name="reservoirs">Reservoirs</string>
    <string name="Canopy">Canopy</string>
    <string name="no_data_found">No Data Found!</string>
    <string name="tolerances">Tolerances and Settings</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="first_time_setup">First Time Setup</string>
    <string name="send_a_string">Send a String</string>
    <string name="Spoof_Data">Spoof Data</string>
    <string name="Print_Data">Print Data</string>
    <string name="When_the">When the</string>
    <string name="is_below">is below</string>
    <string name="i_want_to">I want to </string>
    <string name="Make_30_Data_Points">"Make 30 Data Points"</string>


    <string name="air_temp_below">When the Air Temperature is below</string>
    <string name="air_temp_above">When the Air Temperature is above</string>
    <string name="hum_below">When the humidity is below</string>
    <string name="hum_above">When the humidity is above</string>
    <string name="TVOC_below">When the TVOCs are measured below</string>
    <string name="TVOC_above">When the TVOCS are measured above</string>
    <string name="CO2_below">When the CO2 content is below</string>
    <string name="CO2_above">When the CO2 content is above</string>
    <string name="Sol_temp">When the solution temp is below</string>
    <string name="Sol_above">When the solution temp is above</string>
    <string name="tds_below">When the TDS are below</string>
    <string name="tds_above">When the TDS are above</string>
    <string name="do_above">When the DO is below</string>
    <string name="do_below">When the DO is above</string>
    <string name="orp_below">When the ORP is below</string>
    <string name="orp_above">When the ORP is above</string>
    <string name="pH_below">When the pH is below</string>
    <string name="pH_above">When the pH is above</string>
    <string name="reservoirs_low">When one of the reservoirs needs refilling</string>
    <string name="light_height">The grow light should be above the canopy</string>


    <string name="send_push">Send a Push Notification</string>
    <string name="turn_on_fans">Turn on Extra Fans</string>
    <string name="turn_off_fans">Turn off Extra Fans</string>
    <string name="turn_on_space_heater">Turn on Space Heater</string>
    <string name="turn_on_extra_air_pump">Turn on Extra Air Pump</string>
    <string name="turn_on_fogger">Turn on Fogger</string>
    <string name="add_floragro">Add 5mL FloraGro</string>
    <string name="add_florabloom">Add 5mL FloraBloom</string>
    <string name="add_floramicro">Add 5mL FloraMicro</string>
    <string name="add_hypochloric">Add 5mL Hypochloric Acid</string>
    <string name="add_peroxide">Add 5mL Hydrogen Peroxide</string>
    <string name="add_water">Add water</string>
    <string name="add_acid">Add Acid</string>
    <string name="add_base">Add Base</string>
    <string name="turn_off_air_pump">Turn Off Air Pump</string>
    <string name="turn_on_heating_element">Turn on Heating Element</string>
    <string name="turn_off_heating_element">Turn off Heating Element</string>
    <string name="turn_off_space_heater">Turn off Space Heater</string>
    <string name="save_changes">Save Changes</string>
    <string name="turn_off_fogger">Turn off Fogger</string>









    <string name="learn_about_canopy"><![CDATA[
    The canopy height is simply how high the top of the plant is, measured from the surface of the growing container.<br><br>
    MyGarden calculates this height based on the current position of the grow light and the relative distance from the grow light to the detected plant.<br>

    "
    ]]></string>
    <string name="learn_about_light_height"><![CDATA[
    The light height is the relative distance of the grow light to the top of the growing chamber.<br><br>

    We recommend keeping the grow light about 15 cm from the top of the canopy, but you can change this setting if you wish.
    "
    ]]></string>

    <string name="learn_about_reservoirs"><![CDATA[
    The MyGarden system has nine reservoirs. <br><br>
    The sensors attached to the reservoirs only detect whether the tanks need to be refilled or not.<br><br>
    The first reservoir is filled with the FloraGro 2-1-6 Nutrient. <br><br>
    The second reservoir is filled with the FloreMicro 5-0-1 Nutrient. <br><br>
    The third reservoir is filled with the FloraBloom 0-5-4 Nutrient. <br><br>
    The fourth reservoir is filled with Hypochlorous Acid.<br><br>
    The fifth reservoir is filled with Hydrogen Peroxide.<br><br>
    The sixth reservoir is filled with tap water.<br><br>
    The seventh reservoir is filled with Base. <br><br>
    The eighth reservoir is filled with Acid.<br><br>
    "
    ]]></string>



    <string name="learn_about_humidity"><![CDATA[
    "Humidity is the measure of water vapor in the air.<br><br>
    It can be measured in a few different ways, but the most common form in this context is called <i>Relative Humidity</i>.<br>
    Relative Humidity is a measure of the water content in the air, relative to a maximum amount physically allowed at the measured temperature. This is traditionally expressed as a percentage; it's the same measurement shown on local weather readings.
    <br><br>It's worth noting that one can decrease the relative humidity of a body of air by increasing the temperature of the air. The air can host more water vapor at higher temperatures.<br><br>

    Humidity that is too low can cause problems with pollination and transpiration. Low Relative Humidities are often identified by plants curling their leaves upwards, like a straw. This occurs so that the plants minimize the contact area with the dry air, mitigating water losses in the plant. <br><br>

    Humidity that is too high is also problematic. At high humidities, that plants lose their ability to expel water vapor from their leaves during the process of transpiration. When this occurs, it is easy to identify water droplets on the leaves.
    Plants that lose ability to transpire will suffer nutrient deficiency problems quickly.
    <br><br>
    In the MyGarden System, low humidities can be addressed by turning on the fogger and decreasing the temperature (if tolerances allow). <br>
    <br>High Humidities can be addressed with increasing air temperatures and turning on auxiliary fans. <br><br>

    If high humidities continue to be a problem, it's recommend to decrease the amount of plants in the grow tent.

    <br><br><b>References</b><br><br>
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humidity">Wikipedia - Humidity</a><br><br>
    <a href="http://flairform.com/hints/humidity.htm">Flair-Form Hydroponics<br><br>
    <a href="http://www.ecogrow.com/learning-center-understanding-relative-humidity-c-283_295.html">EcoGrow Enterprises<br><br>
    <a href="https://www.hydroponics-simplified.com/how-to-grow-hydroponics.html">Hydroponics Simplified<br><br>



    "
    ]]></string>



    <string name="learn_about_co2"><![CDATA[
    "Carbon Dioxide (CO₂) is used by plants to convert light energy into chemical energy in a process called <i>photosynthesis</i>.<br><br>

    Inadequate supply of CO₂ can be a limiting factor in the growth plants, so it's an important quantity to monitor.<br><br>

    It is thought that some plants can benefit from additional CO₂ supplementation during particular phases of their lifecycles; we recommend consulting some of the references below if you'd like to consider augmenting your MyGarden with a CO₂ supply.
    <br><br>
    The earth naturally has a CO₂ concentration of about 400ppm. CO₂ concentrations below 200ppm are thought to halt photosynthesis.
    <br><br>
    In this release of the MyGarden System, there are no actuators that can manipulate the CO₂ content of the garden's air.

    <br><br><b>References</b><br><br>
    <a href="http://www.simplyhydro.com/effective_co2_use.htm">Simply Hydro - Effective CO₂ Use</a><br><br>
    <a href="https://www.hydroponics.net/learn/co2_calculator.php">CO₂ Calculator - Greentrees Hydroponics<br><br>
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photosynthesis">Wikipedia - Photosynthesis</a><br><br>
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carbon_dioxide_in_Earth%27s_atmosphere">Wikipedia - Carbon Dioxide in Earth's Atmosphere</a><br><br>



    "
    ]]></string>

    <string name="learn_about_orp"><![CDATA[
    In the context of hydroponic gardening, <i>Oxidation-Reduction Potential</i> can be thought of as a measure of how sterile a solution is. Sometimes ORP is referred to as "killing power", referring to the tendency to kill microorganisms inside of the nutrient solution.<br><br>

    ORP is typically measured in milliVolts, and can be positive or negative. A more positive mV measurement means the solution is more sterile, and a lower (more negative) mV measurement means that the solution is more hospitable to microorganisms. <br><br>

    Too low of an ORP can mean that the system is susceptible to pathogens such as <i>Pythium</i> and <i>E. Coli</i>. Too high of an ORP means that the plant itself will suffer from the oxidation effect of the nutrient solution.<br><br>
    The MyGarden system is designed to grow in sterile environment. Not all hydroponic systems are designed this way; some utilize beneficial bacteria or aquatic wildlife to maintain system functionality.<br><br>

    Hydrogen Peroxide, contained in reservoir 5, can be used to increase the ORP. It will also increase the Dissolved Oxygen and pH, so the system will only add this to the nutrient solution if all three parameters need adjustment.

    Hypochlorous Acid, contained in reservoir 4, is used to increase the ORP most often because it has fewer effects on other system parameters. <br><br>

    Diluting the nutrient solution with water (reservoir 6), increasing the temperature, and decreasing the Dissolved Oxygen will decrease the ORP. <br><br>

    We recommend maintaining MyGarden in the range of +400 to +500 mV to ensure safety.





    <br><br><b>References<br><br></b>
    <a href="https://www.maximumyield.com/the-power-of-orp-how-to-get-the-most-out-of-oxidation-reduction-potentials-in-your-hydroponic-system/2/1316">Maximum Yield - The Power of ORP </a><br><br>
    <a href="http://scienceinhydroponics.com/2017/03/what-is-an-orp-meter-and-why-is-it-useful-in-hydroponics.html">Science in Hydroponics - ORP</a>


    ]]></string>

    <string name="learn_about_pH"><![CDATA[
    pH is a unitless number used to describe the amount of Hydrogen Ions and Hydroxide Ions there are in a solution. This is measured on a logarithmic scale from 1 to 14. <br><br>
    Solutions with a pH from 1 to 7 are called acids, which means they have an excess amount of Hydrogen Ions. Solutions with a pH from 7 to 14 are called bases, defined by having an excess of Hydroxide ions.<br><br>
    For the purposes of a soilless hydroponic garden, pH can be thought of as a chemical property of the nutrient solution that needs to be maintained so that the plant can grow.

    Most plants thrive in a slightly acidic pH of 5.5-6.0, but can survive in environments of pH 5.0 to 7.5.<br><br>

    If the pH is too high or too low, nutrients will precipitate out of the solution can causes deficiencies in the plant.

    Low pH is adjusted by MyGarden by pumping base (Reservoir 7) into the system.<br>
    High pH is adjusted by MyGarden by adding acid (Reservoir 8) into the system. <br>

    Each type of plant has a particular pH that it grows best in; it is recommended that you research your crop and adjust the app settings to accommodate.<br><br>

    <b>References<br><br></b>
    <a href="http://www.simplyhydro.com/ph.htm">Simply Hydroponics - Maximum pH</a><br><br>
    <a href="http://www.simplyhydro.com/ph.htm">Manic Botanix - pH in Hydroponics</a>


    ]]></string>



    <string name="learn_about_air_temp"><![CDATA[
        "Maintaining the proper ambient air temperature is critical for the well–being of a hydroponic garden.<br><br>Plant metabolism requires a cooldown at night;
        it is thought that a difference of about 10°F down is ideal. Turning off the grow–lights during this colder period will produce optimal plant growth.<br><br>If you're growing this indoors, we recommend that you set your thermostat to be cooler at night to accommodate. Air Temperatures are traditionally controlled by ventilation and artificial heating, which is what My Garden implements.<br><br>For warm–season crops and herbs [tomatoes, peppers, eggplants, cucumbers, beans, squash, melons, herbs]<br><br>"
        <bold>"Daytime: </bold>70–80°F;<br> <bold>Nighttime</bold>: 60–70°F<br> <bold>Absolute Max Temp</bold>: 86°F<br><br>""For cool–season crops [broccoli, cabbage, lettuces, endive, peas, spinach, green onions]<br><br>"

        "<b>Daytime</b>: 60–70°F<br> <b>Nighttime</b>: 50–60 °F<br> <b>Absolute minimum temp</b>: 40°F<br><br>"

        "Regardless of the crop grown, it never advised to allow the temperature of the garden reach temperatures of 86°F or above. This will induce a process called <i>photorespiration</i>,
        where the plant's internal sugar supplies are needlessly depleted, retarding growth.<br><br>It's also important to keep daytime temperatures above 70°F; temperatures below that will suppress the vegetative processes of <i>photosynthesis</i> and <i>respiration</i>.<br><br>Plants don't photosynthesize at night. So, the respiration rate ought to be reduced because plants cannot store the product of this process. Respiration rates are reduced by cooling the temperature below 70°F.<br><br>"
        <br><b>References<br><br></b>
        <a href="https://www.hydroponics-simplified.com/how-to-grow-hydroponics.html">Hydroponics-Simplified<br><br></a>
        <a href="http://flairform.com/hints/temperature_air.htm">Flair-Form Hydroponics<br><br></a>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photorespiration#Increased_temperature">Wikipedia - Photorespiration<br><br></a>
     ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="learn_about_tds"><![CDATA[
        "There are a few methods to describe the concentration of nutrients in a hydroponic growing solution.<br><br>

        The MyGarden system comes with a parts-per-million sensor, which detects one part by weight of the mineral in one million parts of solution. <br><br>

        While the 3-2-1 nutrient is being used, we recommend a TDS of 1350-1450 ppm. <br><br>
        While the 2-2-2 nutrient is being used, we recommend a TDS of 1300-1400 ppm. <br><br>
        While the 1-2-3 nutrient is being used, we recommend a TDS of 1250-1350 ppm. <br><br>

        If the concentration is nutrients is too high, your plants may experience fertilizer burn. If the concentration is too low, plants may not grow optimally, or at all. <br><br>
        Different plants require different strengths of nutrient solution, so it is important to research the specific needs of the plant in question. <br>

        <br><br><b>References<br><br></b>
        <a href="https://generalhydroponics.com/tds-ec-ppm">General Hydroponics<br><br></a>
        <a href="http://www.homehydrosystems.com/ph_tds_ppm/ph_vegetables_page.html">Home Hydro Systems - List of Vegetable Parameters<br><br></a>
        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="learn_about_dissolved_oxygen"><![CDATA[
        "Although plants don't have lungs, they can still die from a lack of oxygen.
        If roots are not exposed to enough oxygen, the plant will become ill and perish.<br><br>

        If there is not enough oxygen available to the roots, the plants will wilt. This is often the first sign of this syndrome, commonly called <i>Root Rot</i>.<br><br>

        Most crops prefer a Dissolved Oxygen level of about 9ppm. There is often fairly wide tolerance, though. A study of lettuce crops (Albright et al, 1996) showed no discernable difference between crops grown in the range of 2.1 ppm to 16.8 ppm.<br><br>

        The Dissolved Oxygen content of tap water is typically around 5 to 7 ppm. Thus, it's necessary to increase the oxygen content of the water to meet the recommended 9ppm. MyGarden includes an air pump which will be enabled whenever low DO levels are detected.<br><br>

        Additionally, a reservoir containing Hydrogen Peroxide is included. Hydrogen Peroxide can be used to increase the dissolved oxygen content of the solution, but it also has the effect of increasing the Oxidation-Reduction Potential and raising the pH. <br><br>So, the use of Hydrogen Peroxide is limited.



        <br><br><b>References<br><br></b>
        <a href="http://www.just4growers.com/stream/hydroponic-growing-techniques/airing-out-the-truth-on-dissolved-oxygen-in-hydroponics.aspx">Just 4 Growers - Dissolved Oxygen<br><br></a>
        <a href="http://www.homehydrosystems.com/nutrients/oxygen_page.html">Home Hydro Systems - Oxygen<br><br></a>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="learn_about_TVOC"><![CDATA[
    A <i> Volatile Organic Compound </i> is a particular type of chemical that turns into a gas at a very low temperature. <br><br>
    VOCs are both naturally-occurring (most scents are VOCs), and man-made. <br><br>
    Some VOCs are thought to be harmful to human health over long exposure periods. <br><br>
    Broadly, VOCs are a measure of air quality, where a smaller concentration is thought to be better. It can also be a measure of smell.<br><br>
    MyGarden does not include actuators to manipulate the VOC concentration. However, the data collected can be useful for research and troubleshooting.
    <br><br><b>References<br><br></b>
    <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Volatile_organic_compound">Wikipedia - Volatile Organic Compound </a><br><br>
    <a href="http://npi.gov.au/resource/total-volatile-organic-compounds">Australian National Pollutant Registry</a>
    ]]></string>


    <string name="learn_about_solution_temp"><![CDATA[
        "The solution temperature is simply the temperature of the liquid that sits below the growing chamber. <br><br>
        The solution temperature should follow the ambient temperature in the garden; it should be warmer during the day, and colder at night.
        If the solution temperature is too high, the plant may suffer from heat stress and wilt.<br><br>

        As solution temperatures increase, the amount of Dissolved Oxygen the solution can host decreases. So, it's also possible that one might see symptoms of Oxygen Deficiency as well.<br><br>

        Low Solution Temperatures will slow plant respiration, which in turn slows growth.

        <br><br><b>References<br><br></b>
        <a href="http://www.homehydrosystems.com/articles/Nutrient%20Solution%20Temperature/Nutrient%20Solution%20Temperature%20is%20Important.html">Home Hydro Systems - Nutrient Solution Temperature<br><br></a>
        <a href="http://simplyhydro.com/nutrient_temp.ht
        m">Simply Hydro - Nutrient Temp<br><br></a>
        ]]>
    </string>



    <string name="action_settings">About</string>

    <!-- Strings related to Settings -->

    <!-- Example General settings -->
    <string name="pref_header_general">General</string>

    <string name="pref_title_social_recommendations">Enable social recommendations</string>
    <string name="pref_description_social_recommendations">Recommendations for people to contact
        based on your message history
    </string>

    <string name="pref_title_display_name">Display name</string>
    <string name="pref_default_display_name">John Smith</string>

    <string name="pref_title_add_friends_to_messages">Add friends to messages</string>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_titles">
        <item>Always</item>
        <item>When possible</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Example settings for Data & Sync -->
    <string name="pref_header_data_sync">Data &amp; sync</string>

    <string name="pref_title_sync_frequency">Sync frequency</string>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_titles">
        <item>15 minutes</item>
        <item>30 minutes</item>
        <item>1 hour</item>
        <item>3 hours</item>
        <item>6 hours</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_values">
        <item>15</item>
        <item>30</item>
        <item>60</item>
        <item>180</item>
        <item>360</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="pref_title_system_sync_settings">System sync settings</string>

    <!-- Example settings for Notifications -->
    <string name="pref_header_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="pref_title_new_message_notifications">New message notifications</string>

    <string name="pref_title_ringtone">Ringtone</string>
    <string name="pref_ringtone_silent">Silent</string>

    <string name="pref_title_vibrate">Vibrate</string>
    <string name="title_activity_light_height">Light Height</string>
    <string name="placeholder_airtemp">placeholder_airtemp</string>
</resources>
